Imagine a world where medical diagnoses are faster, more accurate,
and more accessible.
This is becoming a reality thanks to the power of
artificial intelligence, specifically neural networks, in medical imaging.
For years, doctors have relied on tools like X-rays, MRIs,
and CT scans to visualize the human body.
Now, neural networks are taking these images to the next
Neural networks are a type of AI that excels at
pattern recognition. Think of them as incredibly sophisticated image analysis
They are trained on massive datasets of medical images, learning
to identify subtle patterns and anomalies that might be invisible
to the human eye.